This medium (CD/DVD/memory stick) was created with the software iQ-VIEW/PRO version 3.1 by:

IMAGE Information Systems Europe GmbH
Lange Str. 16
18055 Rostock
Germany


iQ-VIEW/PRO version 3.1 is manufactured by:

IMAGE Information Systems Europe GmbH
Lange Str. 16
18055 Rostock
Germany

Email: info@image-systems.biz 
Web: www.image-systems.biz 


The medium (CD/DVD/memory stick) contains the following folder structure:

1. Root directory
It contains all files for running the patient data burned on the medium with either the iQ-LITE viewer or from a web browser, including the instructions for use. It also contains the 'DICOMDIR', the main table of the database.

2. DICOM
In this folder are saved the DICOM image data. A specific folder structure is used: Each study is filed in a separate folder which is comprised of individual folders for the different series that are included in the study. The series folders then contain the individual images.

3. IHE_PDI
This folder contains the 'BANNER.JPG', which is used as a label for both the iQ-LITE viewer and the top of the INDEX.HTM page. Further you will find here the html sub-pages for study level and series level as well as the individual images as JPEG. 

4. REPORTS
The DICOM structured reports in an html web view are stored here.

The medium (CD/DVD/memory stick) may include the iQ-LITE DICOM viewer version 3.1. The software runs on Microsoft(r) Windows(r) 7, 8/8.1 and 10. 

===============================================

System requirements: 

* Intel Multi-Core CPU with ≥ 2 GHz
* ≥ 4 GB main memory 
* ≥ 500 GB S-ATA II hard disk drive (HDD)
* Graphics card, resolution of 1280x1024 or more, True Color mode (24 bit) or at least 8 bit gray output, any nVidia or ATI graphics card with ≥ 1 GB RAM 
* 1x digital color or grayscale display ≥ 19” for demonstration; 1 or 2 high-resolution displays as diagnostic displays with up to 3 MP
* Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 8.1, Windows 10; each with 32 or 64 bit; for all OS Professional edition or higher, with latest service packs 
* Adobe Acrobat Reader, version XI
* CD/DVD drive for the reading of iQ-LITE patient media
* Mouse with scroll wheel
* PostScript printer
* DELL or HP hardware

Also pay attention to the hardware requirements of the supported Microsoft Windows versions. Check the Microsoft website at www.microsoft.com for further details.

The web content on the CD/DVD/memory stick can be viewed using the following web browsers: 

* Internet Explorer (any version, preferably latest version for used OS)
* Mozilla Firefox (any version, preferably latest version for used OS)
* Google Chrome (any version, preferably latest version for used OS)

For additional system requirements refer to the iQ-LITE 3.1 Administration Guide. This includes the following topics:

* Specific system requirements for Unicode languages
* DICOM storage format for media
* Specific system requirements for display of DICOM-encapsulated PDF objects	
* Ensuring system security

===============================================

iQ-LITE version 3.1 is manufactured by:

IMAGE Information Systems Europe GmbH
Lange Str. 16
18055 Rostock
Germany

Email: info@image-systems.biz 
Web: www.image-systems.biz 


Information regarding the intended use of the software:

iQ-LITE is a module of iQ-VIEW and iQ-VIEW PRO, but can also be integrated directly into burning stations and CD/DVD robots. It functions as DICOM viewer placed onto portable media, such as CD, DVD or memory stick and reads imaging studies that also exist on the medium. 

Referring and treating physicians and veterinarians with radiological training use iQ-LITE for digital reading, viewing and reviewing of diagnostic medical images in order to detect and diagnose physiological conditions of humans or animals. The aim is to view medical imaging evidence and reports as a basis for therapy decisions. Other healthcare professionals may use iQ-LITE for image viewing without diagnostic intention. Patients are not intended to use the application.

As the application runs directly from the medium on which it is placed, there is no special knowledge needed concerning the installation of the device. For its integration into burning stations and CD/DVD robots, IT/PACS administrators should consult the iQ-LITE Administration Guide for the proper procedure.

Refer to the iQ-LITE Instructions for Use for more comprehensive details regarding the purpose of iQ-LITE, for an analysis of the intended patient population and the user groups and for information about the use conditions and contraindications.

===============================================

END-USER SOFTWARE LICENSE AGREEMENT 4.0 rev. 001R

Scope: iQ-LITE 3.1 as a component of iQ-SYSTEM PACS 1.4


1.	INTRODUCTION
This License Agreement ("Agreement") is a legal agreement between you (either an individual or a legal entity) ("Licensee", "you", "your", as context requires) and 

IMAGE Information Systems Europe GmbH 
Lange Str. 16, 18055 Rostock, Germany

and where applicable its suppliers and licensors (collectively "IMAGE") for the software ("Software") and associated documentation ("Documentation"). BY INSTALLING, COPYING, DOWNLOADING, ACCESSING, OR OTHERWISE USING THE SOFTWARE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE FOLLOWING TERMS AND CONDITIONS. PLEASE READ THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS CAREFULLY AS THEY GOVERN YOUR USE OF THE SOFTWARE. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this Agreement, please do NOT install the Software and immediately destroy any copies of the Software and Documentation in your possession.

2.	GRANT OF LICENSE 
IMAGE hereby grants to you a personal, limited, non-exclusive, non-sub-licensable, non-transferable, non-assignable license to use the Software, in machine executable object code form, and any related Documentation as follows:

2.1 EVALUATION/TRIAL LICENSE
You may install and use one copy of the Software on a single computer within your organization for evaluation and testing purposes during the evaluation period. The evaluation/trial Software shall not be used for commercial purposes. THE SOFTWARE MAY CONTAIN A DISABLING MECHANISM THAT WILL PREVENT IT FROM BEING USED AFTER THE EVALUATION PERIOD. YOU MUST NOT TAMPER WITH THE DISABLING MECHANISM OF THE SOFTWARE. After the evaluation period if you do not order the registered version of the Software (which may involve a separate payment) you must remove/destroy the Software and Documentation.

2.2 DEMO LICENSE
You may install and use one copy of the Software on a single computer within your organization for evaluation and demonstration purposes during the demonstration period. The demo Software shall not be used for commercial purposes. THE SOFTWARE MAY CONTAIN A DISABLING MECHANISM THAT WILL PREVENT IT FROM BEING USED AFTER THE DEMONSTRATION PERIOD. YOU MUST NOT TAMPER WITH THE DISABLING MECHANISM OF THE SOFTWARE. After the demonstration period if you do not extend, update, or upgrade the demo Software or order the full version of the Software (which may involve a separate payment) you must remove/destroy the Software and Documentation.

2.3 FULL LICENSE
You may: (i) install and use one copy of the Software on a single computer within your organization; and (ii) make one copy of the Software and Documentation for back-up and archival purposes only, provided that any copy must contain all of the original Software and Documentation's proprietary notices. If you wish to use additional copies of the Software, you must obtain additional licenses from IMAGE for each computer on which the Software is installed.

2.4 CONCURRENT LICENSE
You may: (i) install and use copies of the Software on a specified number of computers within your organization and local network; and (ii) you may only use the Software with one user simultaneously. If you wish to use the Software with more than one user simultaneously or in different networks, you must obtain additional licenses from IMAGE.

3.	LICENSE RESTRICTIONS
a) All rights not expressly granted are reserved.

b) You may not: (i) permit other individuals or entities to use or have access to the Software except under the terms of this Agreement; (ii) modify, translate, reverse engineer, decompile, disassemble (except to the extent that this restriction is expressly prohibited by law) or create derivative works based upon the Software or Documentation; (iii) copy the Software or Documentation (except for back-up or archival purposes); (iv) rent, lease, lend, assign, or otherwise transfer rights to the Software or Documentation; or (v) remove any proprietary notices or labels on the Software or Documentation. Any such prohibited use shall immediately terminate your license to the Software.

c) You agree that you shall only use the Software and Documentation in a manner that complies with all applicable laws, regulations etc. in the jurisdictions in which you use the Software and Documentation, including, but not limited to, applicable restrictions concerning medical uses and copyright and other intellectual property rights. 

d) The Software or the use of the Software may be subject to legal or regulatory provisions related to products used in the Healthcare Industry. Prior to using the Software, it is your responsibility to ensure that your use of the Software will not violate any legal or regulatory provisions. Please contact IMAGE to determine the most recent information regarding legal and regulatory approvals.

e) The use of the Software is intended only for use with properly authorized content. Content files, including, but not limited to images, which are viewed using the Software, may be protected by copyright laws or other laws of any jurisdiction and are used at your own risk.

f) You may only use the Software for your internal purposes. You may not use the Software in any way to provide services, or as part of any application service, provider service or other similar commercial service or application in which third parties have access to the Software.

4.	UPDATES/ERRORS
IMAGE reserves the right at any time to, but is not obligated to, correct errors, alter features, specifications, capabilities, functions, release dates, general availability or other characteristics of the Software ("Updates"). You agree that you may not have access to such Updates without separate payment or through a separate support agreement. If any such Updates are provided to you by IMAGE, such Updates will be considered a part of the Software and subject to the terms and conditions of this Agreement. You agree and understand that although IMAGE takes steps to prevent errors, the Software may contain errors affecting proper operation.

5.	TITLE
Title, ownership rights, and intellectual property rights in and to the Software and Documentation shall remain with IMAGE. The Software is protected by the copyright laws of Germany, the European Union and by international copyright treaties. Title, ownership rights and intellectual property rights in and to any content used with the Software shall be retained by the applicable content owner and may be protected by applicable copyright or other law. IMAGE also retains all rights, titles, and interests in and to the trademarks, trade names, logos, and icons (collectively "Marks") used in or identifying the Software or its features. The use of Marks without the prior written permission of IMAGE is strictly prohibited. Other trademarks are either registered trademarks or trademarks of their respective owners. 

6.	LIMITED WARRANTY AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITIES
IMAGE warrants that the Software will perform in accordance with the Documentation for a period of: (a) thirty (30) days for the demo and evaluation versions and (b) twelve (12) months for the full version starting from the date of receipt. Subject to section 4 above, IMAGE will make commercially reasonable efforts to correct any failure of the Software to perform in accordance with the Documentation. Accordingly, the Licensee is responsible to ensure that only the latest released version of the Software is purchased and in use.

DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY & LIMIT OF LIABILITY. TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, THE ABOVE LIMITED WARRANTY IS GIVEN IN LIEU OF ALL OTHER WARRANTIES, REMEDIES AND CONDITIONS, WHETHER ORAL OR WRITTEN, STATUTORY, EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED. IMAGE FURTHER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION TO ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE OR NONINFRINGEMENT TO THE MAXIMUM EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW. IN NO EVENT SHALL IMAGE BE LIABLE FOR ANY CONSEQUENTIAL, INCIDENTAL, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, OR OTHER DAMAGES WHATSOEVER (INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION TO, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF PROFITS, SERVICE INTERRUPTION, LOSS OF INFORMATION, OR OTHER PECUNIARY LOSS) ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR THE USE OF OR INABILITY TO USE THE SOFTWARE OR DOCUMENTATION, EVEN IF IMAGE HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES. IMAGE'S TOTAL LIABLITY FOR ANY DIRECT DAMAGES SHALL NOT EXCEED FIVE DOLLARS ($5.00). AS SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF LIABILITY FOR CONSEQUENTIAL OR INCIDENTAL DAMAGES, THE ABOVE LIMITATION(S) MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU.

7.	INDEMNIFICATION
The Software is not intended to replace the skill and judgement of a qualified medical practitioner and should only be used by people that have been appropriately trained in the Software’s functions, capabilities and limitations. For example, and without limitation to, various functions of the Software, including Maximum/Minimum Intensity Projection (MIP) and Multi-Planar Reconstruction (MPR) are intended for use only as a supplement to two-dimensional medical image display techniques. You agree to exonerate, indemnify and defend IMAGE, its suppliers, officers, directors and employees, from and against any losses, damages, fines and expenses (including attorneys' fees and costs) arising out of or relating to your use of the Software. THE ENTIRE RISK ARISING OUT OF YOUR USE OF THE SOFTWARE AND DOCUMENTATION REMAINS WITH YOU.

8.	TERMINATION
This License Agreement will automatically terminate if you fail to comply with any term hereof. No notice shall be required from IMAGE to effect such termination. You may also terminate this License Agreement at any time by notifying IMAGE in writing of the termination. Without prejudice to any other rights, upon any termination of this License Agreement, you shall immediately discontinue use of the Software and Documentation and shall within three (3) days return to IMAGE, or certify destruction of, all full or partial copies of the Software, Documentation and related materials.

9.	REPLACEMENT/MIGRATION LICENSES
IMAGE reserves the right to impose charges for replacement and migration licenses. 

The following rules apply for hardware fingerprint based software licenses in the event of one of the following circumstances: 

a) If a replacement license key for a license covered by an Annual Service Package is required for migrating the Software to a new PC or reformatting the media where the Software is installed, and you provide IMAGE with the uninstall code beforehand, one replacement license key per contractual year will be provided free of charge. All subsequent replacement licenses will be invoiced according to the regulations stated in this chapter.

b) If a replacement license key for a license covered by an Annual Service Package is required due to a PC failure, and you provide IMAGE with the original license activation data (this includes the original hardware fingerprint, registration name, and activation key), one replacement license key per contractual year is provided free of charge. All subsequent replacement licenses will be invoiced according to the regulations stated in this chapter. 

c) If a replacement license key for a license not covered by an Annual Service Package is required for migrating the Software to a new PC or reformatting the media where the Software is installed, and you provide IMAGE with the software uninstall code beforehand, the standard fee according to the valid MSR price list will apply. 

d) If a replacement license key for a license not covered by an Annual Service Package is required for migrating the Software to a new PC or reformatting the media where the Software is installed, and you cannot provide IMAGE with the uninstall code beforehand, a processing fee for lost licenses according to the valid MSR price list will apply. 

e) If a replacement license key for a license not covered by an Annual Service Package is required due to a PC failure, and you provide IMAGE with the original license activation data (this includes the original hardware fingerprint, registration name, and activation key), the standard fee according to the valid MSR price list will apply. 

f) If a replacement license key for a license not covered by an Annual Service Package is required due to a PC failure, and you cannot provide IMAGE with the original license activation data, a processing fee for lost licenses according to the valid MSR price list will apply. 

The following rules apply in the event of one of the following circumstances for file based software licenses: 

g) If a replacement license file is required for migrating the Software to a new PC or reformatting the media where the Software is installed, and you provide IMAGE with the original license file beforehand, the standard fee according to the valid MSR price list will apply. 

h) If a replacement license file is required due to a PC failure, and you provide IMAGE with the original license file, the standard fee according to the valid MSR price list will apply. 

i) If a replacement license file is required due to a PC failure, and you cannot provide IMAGE with the original license file, a processing fee for lost licenses according to the valid MSR price list will apply.

10.	MISCELLANEOUS
This Agreement shall constitute the complete and exclusive agreement between the Parties, notwithstanding any variance with any other written instrument submitted by you, whether formally rejected by IMAGE or not. The terms and conditions contained in this Agreement may not be modified except in a writing duly signed by you and an authorized representative of IMAGE. This Agreement is exclusive to you, and may not be transferred without IMAGE's express written consent. If any provision of this Agreement is held to be unenforceable for any reason, such provision shall be reformed only to the extent necessary to make it enforceable, and such decision shall not affect the enforceability of such provision under other circumstances, or of the remaining provisions hereof under all circumstances. The parties specifically acknowledge and agree that this Agreement be drafted and fully enforceable as written in the English language. This Agreement shall be governed by the laws of Germany, without regard to conflicts of law provisions, and you hereby consent to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts sitting in Rostock, Germany. To the extent that you have breached or have indicated your intention to breach this Agreement in any manner which violates or may violate IMAGE's intellectual property rights, or may cause continuing or irreparable harm to IMAGE (including, but not limited to, any breach that may impact IMAGE's intellectual property rights, or a breach by reverse engineering), IMAGE may seek legal action, or any other appropriate action, in any court of competent jurisdiction. This Agreement will not be governed by the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods, the application of which is hereby expressly excluded.

===============================================

---------------------------------------------------------------------------

THIRD PARTY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY CLAIMS FOR iQ-LITE 3.0.0

---------------------------------------------------------------------------

Some tools of the DCMTK from OFFIS, Oldenburg, Germany are used. Read their license:

COPYRIGHT

Unless otherwise specified, the DCMTK software package has the following copyright:

/*
*  Copyright (C) 1994-2010, OFFIS
 *
 *  This software and supporting documentation were developed by
 *
 *   OFFIS e.V.
 *   R&D Division Health
 *   Escherweg 2
 *   D-26121 Oldenburg, Germany
 *
 *  THIS SOFTWARE IS MADE AVAILABLE,  AS IS,  AND OFFIS MAKES NO  WARRANTY
 *  REGARDING  THE  SOFTWARE,  ITS  PERFORMANCE,  ITS  MERCHANTABILITY  OR
 *  FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR USE, FREEDOM FROM ANY COMPUTER DISEASES  OR
 *  ITS CONFORMITY TO ANY SPECIFICATION. THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO QUALITY AND
 *  PERFORMANCE OF THE SOFTWARE IS WITH THE USER.
 *
 *  Copyright of the software  and  supporting  documentation  is,  unless
 *  otherwise stated, owned by OFFIS, and free access is hereby granted as
 *  a license to  use  this  software,  copy  this  software  and  prepare
 *  derivative works based upon this software.  However, any distribution
 *  of this software source code or supporting documentation or derivative
 *  works  (source code and  supporting documentation)  must  include  the
 *  three paragraphs of this copyright notice.
 *
 */

Some portions of the DCMTK software package are derived from earlier versions of this software with the following copyright, and can be identified by the following copyright notice located in each source file:

/*
 *  Copyright (C) 1993/1994, OFFIS, Oldenburg University and CERIUM
 *
 *  This software and supporting documentation were
 *  developed by
 *
 *    Institut OFFIS
 *    Bereich Kommunikationssysteme
 *    Westerstr. 10-12
 *    26121 Oldenburg, Germany
 *
 *    Fachbereich Informatik
 *    Abteilung Prozessinformatik
 *    Carl von Ossietzky Universitaet Oldenburg
 *    Ammerlaender Heerstr. 114-118
 *    26111 Oldenburg, Germany
 *
 *    CERIUM
 *    Laboratoire SIM
 *    Faculte de Medecine
 *    2 Avenue du Pr. Leon Bernard
 *    35043 Rennes Cedex, France
 *
 *  for CEN/TC251/WG4 as a contribution to the Radiological
 *  Society of North America (RSNA) 1993 Digital Imaging and
 *  Communications in Medicine (DICOM) Demonstration.
 *
 *  THIS SOFTWARE IS MADE AVAILABLE, AS IS, AND NEITHER OFFIS,
 *  OLDENBURG UNIVERSITY NOR CERIUM MAKE ANY WARRANTY REGARDING
 *  THE SOFTWARE, ITS PERFORMANCE, ITS MERCHANTABILITY OR
 *  FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR USE, FREEDOM FROM ANY COMPUTER
 *  DISEASES OR ITS CONFORMITY TO ANY SPECIFICATION.  THE
 *  ENTIRE RISK AS TO QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF THE SOFTWARE
 *  IS WITH THE USER.
 *
 *  Copyright of the software and supporting documentation
 *  is, unless otherwise stated, jointly owned by OFFIS,
 *  Oldenburg University and CERIUM and free access is hereby
 *  granted as a license to use this software, copy this
 *  software and prepare derivative works based upon this
 *  software. However, any distribution of this software
 *  source code or supporting documentation or derivative
 *  works (source code and supporting documentation) must
 *  include the three paragraphs of this copyright notice.
 *
 */


Some other parts of this software within the dcmtk/dcmnet sub-package related to the DICOM Upper Layer Protocol are derived from software developed for the RSNA'93 DICOM demonstration and kindly made available to us by the Mallinckrodt Institute of Radiology. Such software can be identified by the following copyright notice located in each affected source file:

/*
 *  Copyright (C) 1993, RSNA and Washington University
 *
 *  The software and supporting documentation for the Radiological
 *  Society of North America (RSNA) 1993 Digital Imaging and
 *  Communications in Medicine (DICOM) Demonstration were developed
 *  at the
 *          Electronic Radiology Laboratory
 *          Mallinckrodt Institute of Radiology
 *          Washington University School of Medicine
 *          510 S. Kingshighway Blvd.
 *          St. Louis, MO 63110
 *  as part of the 1993 DICOM Central Test Node project for, and
 *  under contract with, the Radiological Society of North America.
 *
 *  THIS SOFTWARE IS MADE AVAILABLE, AS IS, AND NEITHER RSNA NOR
 *  WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY MAKE ANY WARRANTY ABOUT THE SOFTWARE, ITS
 *  PERFORMANCE, ITS MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR
 *  USE, FREEDOM FROM ANY COMPUTER DISEASES OR ITS CONFORMITY TO ANY
 *  SPECIFICATION. THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO QUALITY AND PERFORMANCE OF
 *  THE SOFTWARE IS WITH THE USER.
 *
 *  Copyright of the software and supporting documentation is
 *  jointly owned by RSNA and Washington University, and free access
 *  is hereby granted as a license to use this software, copy this
 *  software and prepare derivative works based upon this software.
 *  However, any distribution of this software source code or
 *  supporting documentation or derivative works (source code and
 *  supporting documentation) must include the three paragraphs of
 *  the copyright notice.
 */


The dcmjpeg sub-package includes an adapted version of the Independent JPEG Group Toolkit Version 6b, which is contained in dcmjpeg/libijg8, dcmjpeg/libijg12 and dcmjpeg/libijg16.  This toolkit is covered by the following copyright.  The original README file for the Independent JPEG Group Toolkit is located in dcmjpeg/docs/ijg_readme.txt.

/*
 *  The authors make NO WARRANTY or representation, either express or implied,
 *  with respect to this software, its quality, accuracy, merchantability, or
 *  fitness for a particular purpose.  This software is provided "AS IS", and you,
 *  its user, assume the entire risk as to its quality and accuracy.
 *
 *  This software is copyright (C) 1991-1998, Thomas G. Lane.
 *  All Rights Reserved except as specified below.
 *
 *  Permission is hereby granted to use, copy, modify, and distribute this
 *  software (or portions thereof) for any purpose, without fee, subject to these
 *  conditions:
 *  (1) If any part of the source code for this software is distributed, then this
 *  README file must be included, with this copyright and no-warranty notice
 *  unaltered; and any additions, deletions, or changes to the original files
 *  must be clearly indicated in accompanying documentation.
 *  (2) If only executable code is distributed, then the accompanying
 *  documentation must state that "this software is based in part on the work of
 *  the Independent JPEG Group".
 *  (3) Permission for use of this software is granted only if the user accepts
 *  full responsibility for any undesirable consequences; the authors accept
 *  NO LIABILITY for damages of any kind.
 *
 *  These conditions apply to any software derived from or based on the IJG code,
 *  not just to the unmodified library.  If you use our work, you ought to
 *  acknowledge us.
 *
 *  Permission is NOT granted for the use of any IJG author's name or company name
 *  in advertising or publicity relating to this software or products derived from
 *  it.  This software may be referred to only as "the Independent JPEG Group's
 *  software".
 *
 *  We specifically permit and encourage the use of this software as the basis of
 *  commercial products, provided that all warranty or liability claims are
 *  assumed by the product vendor.
 */

----------------------------------------------------------

The color quantization code in module dcmimage (dcmquant and the related classes) is derived from code written by Jef Poskanzer for the NetPBM toolkit which has the following copyright:

/*
 * Copyright (C) 1989, 1991 by Jef Poskanzer.
 *
 * Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software and its
 * documentation for any purpose and without fee is hereby granted, provided
 * that the above copyright notice appear in all copies and that both that
 * copyright notice and this permission notice appear in supporting
 * documentation.  This software is provided "as is" without express or
 * implied warranty.
 */

----------------------------------------------------------

The code for the OFStandard::strlcpy and OFStandard::strlcat helper functions in ofstd/libsrc/ofstd.cc has been derived from the BSD implementation of strlcpy() and strlcat() and which carries the following copyright notice:

/*
 *  Copyright (c) 1998 Todd C. Miller <Todd.Miller(at)courtesan.com>
 *  All rights reserved.
 *
 *  Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
 *  modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions
 *  are met:
 *  1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
 *     notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
 *  2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright
 *     notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the
 *     documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.
 *  3. The name of the author may not be used to endorse or promote products
 *     derived from this software without specific prior written permission.
 *
 *  THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED ''AS IS'' AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES,
 *  INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY
 *  AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
 *  THE AUTHOR BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL,
 *  EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO,
 *  PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS;
 *  OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY,
 *  WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR
 *  OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF
 *  ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
 */

----------------------------------------------------------

The code for the OFStandard::atof helper function in ofstd/libsrc/ofstd.cc has been derived from an implementation which carries the following copyright notice:

/*
 *  Copyright 1988 Regents of the University of California
 *  Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software and
 *  its documentation for any purpose and without fee is hereby granted,
 *  provided that the above copyright notice appear in all copies.  The
 *  University of California makes no representations about the
 *  suitability of this software for any purpose.  It is provided "as
 *  is" without express or implied warranty.
 *
 *
 *  The code for OFStandard::ftoa has been derived
 *  from an implementation which carries the following copyright notice:
 *
 *  Copyright (c) 1988 Regents of the University of California.
 *  All rights reserved.
 *
 *  Redistribution and use in source and binary forms are permitted
 *  provided that the above copyright notice and this paragraph are
 *  duplicated in all such forms and that any documentation,
 *  advertising materials, and other materials related to such
 *  distribution and use acknowledge that the software was developed
 *  by the University of California, Berkeley.  The name of the
 *  University may not be used to endorse or promote products derived
 *  from this software without specific prior written permission.
 *  THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED ``AS IS'' AND WITHOUT ANY EXPRESS OR
 *  IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION, THE IMPLIED
 *  WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTIBILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.
 */

----------------------------------------------------------

The "Base64" encoder/decoder in ofstd/libsrc/ofstd.cc has been derived from an implementation which carries the following copyright notice:

/*
 *  Copyright (c) 1999, Bob Withers - bwit(at)pobox.com
 *
 *  This code may be freely used for any purpose, either personal or commercial,
 *  provided the authors copyright notice remains intact.
 */

----------------------------------------------------------

# TurboPower Abbrevia

License: Mozilla Public License Version 1.1 https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/MPL/1.1/
No changes were made to the original source code.

The Initial Developer of the Original Code is TurboPower Software

Portions created by TurboPower Software are Copyright (C) 1997-2002. All Rights Reserved.

----------------------------------------------------------

# TChromeTabs

License: Mozilla Public License Version 1.1 https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/MPL/1.1/
No changes were made to the original source code.

The initial developer of the original code is Easy-IP AS (Oslo, Norway, www.easy-ip.net),
written by Paul Spencer Thornton (paul.thornton@easy-ip.net, www.easy-ip.net).

Portions created by Easy-IP AS are Copyright (C) 2012 Easy-IP AS. All Rights Reserved.

----------------------------------------------------------

# Mustangpeak Common Library
# Mustangpeak EasyListView
# Mustangpeak VirtualShellTools

License: Mozilla Public License Version 1.1 https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/MPL/1.1/
No changes were made to the original source code.

The initial developer of this code is Jim Kueneman <jimdk@mindspring.com>

----------------------------------------------------------

# VCL Styles Utils

http://code.google.com/p/vcl-styles-utils/

License: Mozilla Public License Version 1.1 https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/MPL/1.1/
No changes were made to the original source code.

The Initial Developer of the Original Code is Rodrigo Ruz V.
Portions created by Rodrigo Ruz V. are Copyright (C) 2012-2013 Rodrigo Ruz V. All Rights Reserved.

----------------------------------------------------------

# Virtual TreeView

License: Mozilla Public License Version 1.1 https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/MPL/1.1/
No changes were made to the original source code.

The initial developer of the original code is digital publishing AG (Munich, Germany, www.digitalpublishing.de), written by Mike Lischke (public@soft-gems.net, www.soft-gems.net).

Portions created by digital publishing AG are Copyright (C) 1999-2001 digital publishing AG. All Rights Reserved.

----------------------------------------------------------

# Synapse TCP/IP library

http://synapse.ararat.cz/

Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

Neither the name of Lukas Gebauer nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission.

THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS “AS IS” AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE REGENTS OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.

----------------------------------------------------------

# The Drag and Drop Component Suite for Delphi

http://melander.dk/delphi/dragdrop/

© 1997-2010 Anders Melander

Creative Commons Attribution-Share Alike 3.0 Unported License

